Guide to the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg, UPG Senate, 1970-present UPG.RG.35
ULS Greensburg
University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg, UPG Senate
1970-present
ULS Greensburg
University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg
UPG.RG.35
10 boxes
Administrative Records of the UPG Senate of the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg, 1970-present.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Custodial History
Transferred from the UPG Senate to the UPG Archives.
Scope and Content Notes
By-laws, Minutes, Council, Committees, Representatives to the Faculty Senate, Secretary, Subject Files, University of Pittsburgh Oakland Senate, University of Pittsburgh Oakland Faculty Assembly
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of the UPG Senate Minutes are available online.
Universities and colleges -- Pennsylvania -- Greensburg -- Records and correspondence; Universities and colleges -– Pennsylvania -– Greensburg -– Administration; University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg
- By-laws, 1970-2011; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  A. Regional Campus Faculty Senate Proposed By-Laws. 1970.
  B. Senate [Faculty Senate] of the University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg.
  1972 (1970 Amended 1972)
  1977, September
  1979, September
  1988, (Proposed changes, February 1988)
  1994 (Approved April 1988; Revised September 1992; Revised February 1994)
  2003 (Approved April 1988; Revised September 1992; Revised February 1994; Revised January 2003)
  2011 (Approved April 1988; Revised September 1992; Revised February 1994; Revised January 2003; Revised January 2011)
  - By-laws, 1970-2011 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 2)
- Minutes, 1970-present; II.
  Includes agendas, reports, resolutions, UPG Senate membership roster, rosters of standing committees, committee vacancies, results of elections; content for individual years may vary.
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1970-1971 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 2)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 31, 1971
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1971-1972 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 2)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 30, 1971
    - UPG Senate Minutes, December 2, 1971
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 10, 1972
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1972-1973 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 2)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, October 6, 1972
    - UPG Senate Minutes, December 1, 1972
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 29, 1973
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 16, 1973
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1973-1974 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 2)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, October 10, 1973
    - UPG Senate Minutes, December 6, 1973
    - UPG Senate Minutes, February 14, 1974
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 29, 1974
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1974-1975 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 2)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 25, 1974
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 20, 1974
    - UPG Senate Minutes, February 6, 1975
    - UPG Senate Minutes, April 2, 1975
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1975-1976 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 2)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, October 2, 1975
    - UPG Senate Minutes, December 4, 1975
    - UPG Senate Minutes, February 19, 1976
    - UPG Senate Minutes, April 7, 1976
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1976-1977 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 2)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 5, 1976
    - UPG Senate Minutes, December 2, 1976
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 4, 1977
    - UPG Senate Minutes, April 12, 1977
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1977-1978 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 2)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, October 28, 1977
    - UPG Senate Minutes, December 12, 1977
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 1, 1978
    - UPG Senate Minutes, April 4, 1978
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1978-1979 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 2)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, October 6, 1978
    - UPG Senate Minutes, December 1, 1978
    - UPG Senate Minutes, February 20, 1979
    - UPG Senate Minutes, April 5, 1979
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1979-1980 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 2)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, October 26, 1979
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 29, 1979
    - UPG Senate Minutes, February 1, 1980
    - UPG Senate Minutes, May, 1980
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1980-1981 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 2)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 7, 1980
    - UPG Senate Minutes, February 10, 1981
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 27, 1981
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1981-1982 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 2)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 28, October 12, October 16, 1981
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 10, 1981
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 28, 1982
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 15, 1982
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1982-1983 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 2)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 28, 1982
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 15, 1982
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 31, 1983
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 29, 1983
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1983-1984 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 2)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, October 3, 1983
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 29, 1983
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 30, 1984
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 29, 1984
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1984-1985 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 2)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, October 8, 1984
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 27, 1984
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 28, 1985
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 26, 1985
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1985-1986 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 2)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 23, 1985
    - UPG Senate Minutes, February 3, 1986
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 25, 1986
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1986-1987 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 2)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 23, 1986
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 24, 1986
    - UPG Senate Minutes, February 3, 1987
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 30, 1987
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1987-1988 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 2)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 14, 1987
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 17, 1987
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 19, 1988
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 21, 1988
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1988-1989 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 2)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 26, 1988
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 15, 1988
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 17, 1989
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 20, 1989
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1989-1990 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 2)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 18, 1989
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 21, 1989
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 29, 1990
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1990-1991 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 2)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 17, 1990
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 13, 1990
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 28, 1991
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1991-1992 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 3)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 16, 1991
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 12, 1991
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 27, 1992
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 24, 1992
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1992-1993 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 3)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 14, 1992
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 3, 1992
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 25, 1993
    - UPG Senate Minutes, April 6, 1993
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1993-1994 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 3)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 20, 1993
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 9, 1993
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 24, 1994
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 30, 1994
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1994-1995 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 3)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 19, 1994
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 8, 1994
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 14, 1995
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1995-1996 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 3)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 19, 1995
    - UPG Senate Minutes, October 30, 1995
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 23, 1996
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 11, 1996
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1996-1997 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 3)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 17, 1996
    - UPG Senate Minutes, October 28, 1996
    - UPG Senate Minutes, February 4, 1997
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 11, 1997
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1997-1998 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 3)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, October 7, 1997
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 10, 1997
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 27, 1998
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 12, 1998
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1998-1999 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 3)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 22, 1998
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 2, 1998
    - UPG Senate Minutes, February 2, 1999
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 1, 1999
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 1999-2000 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 3)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 28, 1999
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 15, 1999
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 25, 2000
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 27, 2000
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 2000-2001 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 3)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, October 2, 2000
    - UPG Senate Minutes, December 5, 2000
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 22, 2001
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 13, 2001
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 2001-2002 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 4)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 24, 2001
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 20, 2001
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 14, 2002
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 12, 2002
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 2002-2003 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 4)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 30, 2002
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 12, 2002
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 13, 2003
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 11, 2003
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 2003-2004 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 4)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 29, 2003
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 11, 2003
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 12, 2004
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 2, 2004
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 2004-2005 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 4)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 28, 2004
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 8, 2004
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 18, 2005
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 21, 2005
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 2005-2006 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 4)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 27, 2005
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 7, 2005
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 17, 2006
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 20, 2006
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 2006-2007 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 4)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 26, 2006
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 6, 2006
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 16, 2007
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 19, 2007
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 2007-2008 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 4)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 24, 2007
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 13, 2007
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 28, 2008
    - UPG Senate Minutes, April 8, 2008
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 2008-2009 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 4)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 16, 2008
    - UPG Senate Minutes, October 27, 2008
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 18, 2008
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 26, 2009
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 3, 2009
    - UPG Senate Minutes, April 10, 2009
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 2009-2010 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 4)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 3, 2009
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 25, 2010
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 16, 2010
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 2010-2011 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 4)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 20, 2010
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 9, 2010
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 24, 2011
    - UPG Senate Minutes, February 8, 2011
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 15, 2011
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 2011-2012 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 4)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 19, 2011
    - UPG Senate Minutes, October 25, 2011
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 30, 2012
    - UPG Senate Minutes, February 28, 2012
    - UPG Senate Minutes, April 26, 2012
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 2012-2013 (Microfilm-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 4)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 25, 2012
    - UPG Senate Minutes, December 11, 2012
    - UPG Senate Minutes, April 25, 2013
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 2013-2014 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 5)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, December 10, 2013
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 27, 2014
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 31, 2014
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 2014-2015 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 5)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 18, 2014
    - UPG Senate Minutes, April 6, 2015
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 2015-2016 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 5)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 9, 2015
    - UPG Senate Minutes, October 8, 2015
    - UPG Senate Minutes, February 15, 2016
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 31, 2016
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 2016-2017 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 5)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, September 20, 2016
    - UPG Senate Minutes, January 31, 2017
    - UPG Senate Minutes, March 27, 2017
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 2017-2018 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 5)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, October 31, 2017
    - UPG Senate Minutes, February 26, 2018
    - UPG Senate Minutes, April 5, 2018
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 2018-2019 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 5)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, November 28, 2018
  - Minutes, Academic Year, 2019-2020
    - UPG Senate Minutes, April 1, 2019 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 5)
    - UPG Senate Minutes, October 22, 2019 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 7, Box 5)
- Council, 1971-2012; III.
  - Minutes, 1971-2012; 1.
    Minutes, 1971/72-2000/01, 2008, 2012
    Some years are missing and early files are incomplete.
    1971/72 List of Senate Council members; no minutes
    1972/73 call to meeting of 9/15/72
    1973/74 calls to meetings of 11/18/73, 2/25/74
    1974/75 agenda meeting 11/5/74; call to meeting and agenda meeting 3/19/75
    1975/76
    1976/77 lacks minutes 3/24/77 meeting
    1977/78
    1978/79 minutes of meeting 9/22/78 only
    1979/80
    1980/81 MISSING
    1981/82 call and agenda meeting of October 21, 1981 only
    1982/83
    1983/84
    1984/85
    1985/86 MISSING
    1986/87 MISSING
    1987/88 calls to meetings, memoranda; lacks minutes of any of the meetings
    1988/89
    1989/90 MISSING
    1990/91 MISSING
    1991/92
    1992/93 unofficial notes of meetings only
    1993/94 unofficial notes of meetings only
    1994/95
    1995/96
    1996/97
    1997/98 minutes for meetings Jan. 15, Feb. 19, 1998
    1998/99 minutes for meetings Sept. 10, 1998, Jan. 15, Feb. 22, 1999
    1999/2000 minutes for meetings Sept. 10, Nov. 2, 1999
    2000/01 minutes for meeting Nov. 20, 2000
    2008, 5/1, 9/5, 12/1
    2012 1/12 Report of Senate council meeting of 1/12/12. Meeting was to review Fall semester activities and to plan the agenda for this term. Includes a document outlining Faculty Office Assignments for Fall 2012 when the SOC opens and contains text of the rationale behind the assignments.
    - Minutes, 1971-2012 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 1)
- Committees, 1971-2016; IV.
  The files of the Committees consist mainly of copies of minutes of the UPG Faculty Senate which contain oral reports from the Committees or items of interest to the Committees. Since the files of the individual Committees may not contain copies of all pertinent or relevant minutes of the UPG Senate, one should consult UPG.RG.35 UPG Senate, Series: Minutes.
  - Academic Computer Usage Committee, 1989; 1.
    Files, 1989. 1 item. Memorandum dtd 4/7/89 to Senate Council. Subject, "Scope of Academic Computer Usage Committee".
    - Academic Computer Usage Committee, 1989 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 2)
  - Academic Standards Committee, 1972-1988; 2.
    Files, 1972-1980, 1986-1988.
    Contain: for the most part consist of minutes of the Faculty Senate meetings with oral reports from the committee; minutes of meeting 2/19/76 have appended the text of an "Academic Review Resolution (as amended)" introduced by Dr. Zimmerman in re academic requirements and approved by the Senate on 2/19/76; Interim Report [1976?] in re required courses and grade inflation; memorandum 2/18/77 from Donald T. Reilly but approved by the permanent members of the English Department in re a review of the composition program and recommendations concerning student literacy; recommendation 12/1/78 of the Academic Standards Committee and Facilities and Supplies Committee regarding the "motion concerning change in the grading policy of UPG"; reports on Awards for Excellence. 1986/87, 1987/88.
    - Academic Standards Committee, 1972-1988 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 2)
  - Affirmative Action Committee, 1974-1987; 3.
    Files, 1974-1982, 1987.
    Contain: minutes of the Faculty Senate meetings which contain oral reports from the committee or discussion of items of interest to the committee; position paper [1975?]. "Minority Recruiting for Greensburg Campus"; memorandum dtd 1/8/76 from Larry J. Whatule to Kenneth Wenger, subject, "Recruitment of Minority Students"; memorandum dtd 2/19/76 from Charles H. Kuhn Jr. to Charles F. Prioleau, subject, "Affirmative Action Request" dealing with personnel practices as they relate to staff positions; report to the AAC dtd 2/20/76 dealing with recruiting; report dtd 4/7/76 from the AAC to UPG Senate, subject, "Findings/recommendations concerning 1) staff hiring, 2) faculty hiring, 3) student admissions, and 4) housing lists with regard to possible discrimination"; AAC suggested guidelines for implementing the "Affirmative Action Policy for the Recruitment, Selection, and Advancement of Personnel at the University of Pittsburgh" on the Greensburg Campus (April, 1977); "Guideline for Affirmative Action, University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg April7, 1976 Revised April 13, 1982"; memorandum dtd 12/12/77 from L.J. Whatule to Senate, subject, "Affirmative Action Report: Student Recruiting"; memorandum dtd 9/27/78 from C.H. Kuhn Jr., subject, "Affirmative Action Update"; Affirmative Action Report dtd 9/16/82 from Guy Rossetti, Dean of Administration; Affirmative Action Report for 1981-82 dtd 9/27/82 from L.J. Whatule; Affirmative Action Report-Faculty Hiring for School Year 1987-88"; memorandum dtd 10/21/87 from L.J. Whatule in re minority recruitment activities 1986-87.
    - Affirmative Action Committee, 1974-1987 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 2)
  - Appointment and Tenure Policies, Ad Hoc Committee on, 1982; 4.
    Files, 1982.
    2 items. Drafts 1/6/82 and 11/3/82 of document in re appointment and tenure policies.
    See Also
    See also: UPG.RG.35 Faculty Welfare Committee; UPG.RG.37 Faculty Affairs. Ser.: Documents in re "University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg Policies and Procedures for Faculty Appointment, Reappointment, Promotion and Conferral of Tenure".
    - Appointment and Tenure Policies, Ad Hoc Committee on, 1982 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 2)
  - Budget Policies Committee, 1975-1983; 5.
    Files, 1975-1983.
    Contain: minutes of the Faculty Senate meetings which have oral reports by the committee or discussion of items of interest to the committee; memorandum dtd 4/5/77 to Full Time Faculty has addendum, "University of Pittsburgh Analysis of Faculty Salary Increases for the Year 1976-1977" as well as information on university and campus budgets; minutes of BPC meeting 1/5/78, 6/9/78; memorandum 11/28/78 in re University's Two Million Dollar Deficit; ltr 5/28/81 from BPC to Pres. Chambers in re "suggested guideline for merit salary increments"; memorandum 2/10/81 from Senate Welfare Committee in re "UPJ Salary Study"; 1983 correspondence and documents between BPC and Pres. Chambers in re 1981-82 Greensburg Faculty increases vis-a-vis twenty responsibility areas within the University of Pittsburgh.
    - Budget Policies Committee, 1975-1983 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 2)
  - Building and Development Committee, 1972-1990; 6.
    Files, 1972, 1974-78, 1980, 1990
    Consist of minutes of the Faculty Senate meetings which contain oral reports by the committee or discussion of items of interest to the committee; UPG Construction and Projects 10-25-90, 11-6-90.
    - Building and Development Committee, 1972-1990 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 2)
  - By-laws Committee, 1971-1988; 7.
    Files, 1971-74, 1977, 1979, 1987-88.
    - By-laws Committee, 1971-1988 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 2)
  - Collective Bargaining Committee, 1975-1976; 8.
    Files, 1975-76.
    Consists of minutes of the Faculty Senate meetings which contain oral reports by the committee or discussion of items of interest to the committee; memorandum dtd 11 February 1976 from Guy Rossetti to all faculty deals with a meeting concerning the upcoming elections on a bargaining agent.
    - Collective Bargaining Committee, 1975-1976 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 2)
  - Course Scheduling, Senate Committee on, 2000; 9.
    Files. 2000
    5 items: Memo 10/3/00 from Mark McColloch in re formation of cmte and MDM memo of 10/17/00 rescheduling meeting; "Rooms at UPG that could be used for classes as of 10/30/00"; Memo 11/21/00 from Pamela Ondeck, Subject: Committee on Usage of Space-Report.
    - Course Scheduling, Senate Committee on, 2000 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 2)
  - Curriculum, Ad Hoc Committee on, 1972-1975; 10.
    Files, 1972, 1974-75.
    Consist principally of minutes of Faculty Senate meeting which contain oral reports by the committee or discussion of items of interest to the committee; contain a copy of a Mar. 24, 1975 report by the committee to all Senate members.
    Day-Degree Programs, Ad Hoc Committee to Study Possibilities for.
    Files, 1972.
    1 item. Minutes of Mar. 10, 1972 Faculty Senate meeting which note the appointment of the committee.
    - Curriculum, Ad Hoc Committee on, 1972-1975 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 2)
  - Educational Policies Committee. [Educational Policies and Planning Committee], 1980-2013; 11.
    Files, 1980, 1987, 2001, 2010, 2013
    Contain: memorandum Feb. 22, 1980 giving election results for the EPC; Nov. 17, 1987 minutes of the Faculty Senate containing oral report of the committee; 1987 report of EPC dealing with policy on Adding/Dropping a course, the CAS General Education Requirement and Third Term Faculty Evaluations; EPC report of Nov. 5, 1987 dealing with "Committee Reports".
    "Classroom Visitation", document dtd 1/22/01]; "Proposal to Change the College Composition 3 Requirement to a W or Discipline-Appropriate Course," November 2010. Proposal dtd Jan. 23, 2013, "allow any course taken for any major, minor, or related area to count toward fulfilling the general distribution..."; Report to the Faculty Senate, Feb., 2013, subjects: 3 credit first-year seminars...; "lack of definition for the various aspects of the general education requirement..."; "Recommendation from the EPC dtd 3/31/14 in re "Twelve-Credit requirement, FC Designation; and Changing Credit Designations.
    - Educational Policies Committee. [Educational Policies and Planning Committee], 1980-2013 (Museum-cabinet 1, Shelf 8, Box 2)
  - Faculty Welfare Committee, 1971-2016; 12.
    See also: UPG.RG.37 Faculty Affairs. Ser.: Documents in re "University of Pittsburgh at Greensburg Policies and Procedures for Faculty Appointment, Reappointment, Promotion and Conferral of Tenure. See also: UPG.RG.35 Ser.: Committees. Appointment and Tenure Policies, Ad Hoc Committee. See also: Ser.: Subject Files. Appointment, Promotion, Tenure.
    Files, 1971-78, 1987, 1993, 2008, 2012-2016
    Contain: minutes of the Faculty Senate meetings which have oral reports by the committee or items of interest to the committee
    1972 committee proposal for "Grant-in Aid Program"
    1/17/73 proposed resolution to Senate Council dealing with third term teaching
    9/17/73 committee "Proposal for Formation of an Ad Hoc Tenure Committee"
    4/2/75 minutes of Faculty Senate which include document titled "Benefits" and document titled "Faculty Summer Grant", a substitution for the document titled "Grant-in Aid Program"